<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-19T19:33:22-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jessica Ip</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hedera Network</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/13/hedera-network.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hedera Network" /><published>2022-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/13/hedera-network</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/13/hedera-network.html">&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:18px&quot;&gt;Having recently read a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blockchain.cs.ucl.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/UCL_CBT_DPS_Q32021_updated-2.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; by the University College London&apos;s Centre for Blockchain Technologies (UCL CBT) that compares the energy footprint of different consensus mechanisms, in which the Hedera network was concluded to have the lowest energy footprint, I became curious to learn more about Hedera, the only non-blockchain distributed ledger technology (DLT) amongst blockchain DLTs in the study (Ethereum 2.0, Algorand, Cardano, Polkadot, and Tezos) and more importantly, how it is allegedly more energy efficient than the other DLTs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:18px&quot;&gt;
Self-proclaimed to be &quot;the most used, sustainable, enterprise-grade public network for the decentralized economy,&quot; Hedera certainly possesses characteristics/components/attributes that set it apart from more well-known examples of DLTs like Bitcoin, Ethereum, and Hyperledger. Chief among them is the fact that it is a hashgraph and not a blockchain. Invented in 2016 by Leemon Baird, Hashgraph is his answer to achieving distributed consensus at scale, with the primary use being targeted at the private corporate sector. Put explicitly, the technology behind blockchain DLTs is blockchain; the technology behind hashgraph DLTs is direct acyclic graph (DAG). The distinction lies in the way that information is disseminated and the consensus mechanism of the underlying technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:18px&quot;&gt;All transactions (hashgraph blocks) are added to the ledger, 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:18px&quot;&gt;
It is difficult to get a sense of how decentralized a network is when there is no existing metric for such a claim. The mere definition of decentralization can be interpreted rather loosely and at vastly different scales. Operating on the belief that decentralization most directly means there is no central authority, then perhaps a governance council comprising of various enterprises (an anomaly in the space of decentralized networks) is Baird&apos;s attempt at getting as close to decentralization as possible. One might find that the participation of Fortune 500 companies and a highly-ranked university (UCL) renders null the principle of decentralization, to which Baird argues that it is precisely this combination of global companies with stake in their own future that enables a decentralized digital economy. 
Is there much difference to those who tout the benefits of decentralization if it&apos;s just anonymous centralization? 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DLT, aBFT, consensus mechanism, currency, permission (permissioned, switching to permissionless)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Having recently read a paper by the University College London&apos;s Centre for Blockchain Technologies (UCL CBT) that compares the energy footprint of different consensus mechanisms, in which the Hedera network was concluded to have the lowest energy footprint, I became curious to learn more about Hedera, the only non-blockchain distributed ledger technology (DLT) amongst blockchain DLTs in the study (Ethereum 2.0, Algorand, Cardano, Polkadot, and Tezos) and more importantly, how it is allegedly more energy efficient than the other DLTs.</summary></entry></feed>